Guide to the American Federation of Teachers Local 200 Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
American Federation of Teachers, Local 200 Records
1927-1982
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
1909
American Federation of Teachers.$bLocal 200 (Seattle, Wash.)
approximately 14 cubic feet (18 boxes)
Records of the Federation
Labor organization of teachers in Seattle public schools since 1927.
Local 200 of American Federation of Teachers was chartered in 1921, a union of classroom teachers in Seattle. Local 200 contained several subgroups throughout its history, and the Seattle Teachers' Association and Seattle Federation of Teachers were very prominent rival organizations within the local during the late 1960s through the 1980s.
Records are divided into four accessions based on when they were donated. Accession numbers are 1909-001, 1909-004, 1909-005, and 1909-006.
Accession 1909-001 is broken into eight series based on its intellectual contents. The accession ranges from 1927-1973.
Series I: Constitutions, 1927-1962.
Series II: Incoming Letters, 1954-1969.
Series III: Outgoing Letters, 1951-1970.
Series IV: General Correspondence and Meeting Minutes, 1954-1969.
Series V: Financial Records, 1941-1970.
Series VI: Reports, 1954-1969.
Series VII: Lists, 1945-1968.
Series VIII: Publications, Leaflets, and Member Petitions, 1946-1973.
Accession 1909-004 is broken into nine series based on its intellectual contents. Series VI is further divided into ten subseries based on various subjects covered within the series. The accession ranges from 1943-1974.
Series I: Reports, 1967-1971.
Series II: Grievances and Employer Relations, 1964-1971.
Series III: Financial Records, 1943-1972.
Series IV: Meeting Minutes, 1949-1971.
Series V: Correspondence, 1951-1971.
Series VI: Subject Files, 1950-1973.
Subseries A: Conventions, 1959-1970.
Subseries B: Organizing, 1969-1971.
Subseries C: Central Area School Council and Community Control of Schools in Central and South Seattle, 1968-1971.
Subseries D: Desegregation and Racial Issues, 1967-1971.
Subseries E: Contract Negotiations and Teacher Benefits, 1950-1971.
Subseries F: King County Labor Council, 1968-1971.
Subseries G: Legislation and Political Action, 1955-1972.
Subseries H: Federations of Teachers from Other States, 1968-1970.
Subseries I: Office Administrative Files, 1963-1971.
Subseries J: School Policy, 1966-1973.
Series VII: Newspapers, 1953-1971.
Series VIII: Photographs, 1964-1969.
Series IX: Publications, Leaflets, and Elections Materials, 1947-1974.
Accession 1909-005 is broken into eleven series based on its intellectual contents. The accession ranges from 1964-1982. Materials within each series remain in their original order.
Series I: Constitutions and By-Laws, 1972-1973.
Series II: Correspondence, 1969-1980.
Series III: Minutes, 1968-1979.
Series IV: Financial Records, 1967-1982.
Series V: Membership, 1971-1976.
Series VI: Publications, 1966-1980.
Series VII: Contract Enforcement, 1968-1979.
Series VIII: Conventions, 1974-1979.
Series IX: Subject Files, 1964-1973.
Series X: School Files, 1968-1976.
Series XI: Committees and Subgroups, 1970-1982.
Accession 1909-006 is broken into three record groups reflecting creating organizations. The first record group is broken into fourteen series based on its intellectual contents, and the second and third record groups contain no further subdivisions. The accession ranges from 1963-1979.
Record Group 1: American Federation of Teachers Local 200, 1963-1979.
Series I: Membership, 1969-1976.
Series II: Correspondence, 1966-1979.
Series III: Minutes, 1969-1972.
Series IV: Financial Records, 1970-1979.
Series V: Grant Applications, 1969-1976.
Series VI: Press Releases, 1969-1973.
Series VII: Newsletters and Mailings, 1969-1977.
Series VIII: Petitions, 1972-1976.
Series IX: Strikes, 1971-1976.
Series X: Speeches and Writings, 1971-1973.
Series XI: Elections, 1971.
Series XII: Clippings, 1976.
Series XIII: Grievance Files, 1963-1976.
Series XIV: Subject Files, 1969-1977.
Record Group 2: American Federation of Teachers Local 200 Executive Board, 1969-1972.
Record Group 3: American Federation of Teachers Local 200: Seattle Minority Teachers Association, 1976.
Consult the scope and content information for each of the accessions listed below.
Consult the access restrictions information for each of the accessions listed below.
Separated Material
Photographs from Accessions 1909-004, 1909-005, and 1909-006 have been removed from their original locations and placed in the
American Federation of Teachers Local 200 Photograph Collection
in the University of Washington Libraries' Special Collections Division.
Miller, Elmer; Morris, William W.; Bottomly, Forbes; Chichester, J. Bernard; Dunn, John,$dfl. 1869-1883; Warren, Kenneth R.; Pangborn, G. Sally; American Federation of Teachers.$bLocal 200 (Seattle, Wash.)$vArchives; Seattle Public Schools; Washington State Federation of Teachers; AFL-CIO.$bKing County Labor Council of Washington; American Federation of Teachers (AFL).$bLocal 200 (Seattle, Wash.).$bExecutive Board; American Federation of Teachers.$bLocal 200 (Seattle, Wash.).$bSeattle Minority Teachers' Association; AFL-CIO.$bWashington State Labor Council; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Teachers' unions$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Teachers' unions$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$vRecords and correspondence; Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Elementary and Secondary Education; Civic Activism; Washington (State); Seattle
- American Federation of Teachers Local 200 records, 1927-1973; 1909-001; 2.6 cubic feet 6 boxes
  Correspondence, reports, newsletters, financial records, minutes, clippings, lists, ephemera.
  Open to all users, but access to portions of the papers restricted. Contact repository for details.
  Seattle Federation of Teachers, via Marjorie Stern, Seattle, May 03, 1972
  - CONSTITUTIONS, 1927-1962; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Constitutions and Bylaws, Multiple American Federation of Teachers Locals, 1927-1962 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - INCOMING CORRESPONDENCE, 1954-1969; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/2-1/34)
    - Cherberg, John, 1968 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Hess, Andy, 1963 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Jackson, Henry M., 1954 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - A - L Incoming Letters, 1956-1969 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Magnuson, Warren G., 1955 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Pelly, Thomas M., 1954-1957 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Rosellini, Albert D., 1957 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - M - R Incoming Letters, 1955-1968 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Seattle Public Schools - Bottomly, Forbes, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Seattle Public Schools - Brock, Frank M., 1963-1968 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Buckley, Dale L., 1968 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Campbell, E.W., 1956-1964 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Chichester, J.B., 1956-1967 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Fissell, Lloyd A., 1966 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Fogg, Billy J., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Greaves, Jack, 1968 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Hanawalt, Frank, 1956 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Morris, William E., 1954-1955 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Nylen, Donald, 1957 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Owen, Frances, 1963 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Reiter, Bernard, 1957 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Selby, Kenneth E., 1956 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Tidwell, Robert A., 1967 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Troxell, Loren, 1964 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Van Devanter, A.T., 1956 (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Wagoner, David E., 1968 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - S Incoming Letters, 1957-1968 (Box-folder 1/28)
    - Washington. Insurance Commissioner, 1967 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Washington. Public Instruction, Superintendent, 1956-1967 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Washington. Discrimination, State Board Against, 1968 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Westland, Jack, 1957 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - T - Z Incoming Letters (1 of 2), 1954-1968 (Box-folder 1/33)
    - T - Z Incoming Letters (2 of 2), 1954-1968 (Box-folder 1/34)
  - OUTGOING CORRESPONDENCE, 1951-1970; SERIES III (Box-folder 1/35-1/36)
    - Outgoing Letters (1 of 2), 1951-1970 (Box-folder 1/35)
    - Outgoing Letters (2 of 2), 1951-1970 (Box-folder 1/36)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE AND MEETING MINUTES, 1954-1969; SERIES IV (Box-folder 1/37-2/6)
    - General Correspondence, 1956-1964 (Box-folder 1/37)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 1/38)
    - General Membership Meeting Minutes, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Meeting Minutes: American Federation of Teachers Representatives and the Superintendent, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - School Board Meeting Minutes (1 of 2), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - School Board Meeting Minutes (2 of 2), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Meeting Minutes: Special Committees and Seattle Central Labor Council, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Agendas, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1941-1970; SERIES V (Box-folder 2/7-3/2; 6/1-6/3)
    - Budgets, 1951-1970 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Check Sheets (1 of 2), 1951-1970 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Check Sheets (2 of 2), 1951-1970 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Salaries, 1951-1970 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Statements of Financial Position, 1951-1970 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1951-1970 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Yearly Record Sheets, 1951-1970 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Yearly Record Sheets, 1951-1970 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Financial Documents, 1954-1970 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Ledger, 1941-1950 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Ledger, 1950-1962 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Ledger, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - REPORTS, 1954-1969; SERIES VI (Box-folder 3/3-3/11)
    - Reports of the Educational Policy Committee, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Proposals by the Seattle Federation of Teachers General Membership and Committees, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - American Federation of Teachers Convention Resolutions, 1954-1967 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Salary Committee, Contract Negotiations and Legislative Reports (1 of 2), 1954-1969 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Salary Committee, Contract Negotiations and Legislative Reports (2 of 2), 1954-1969 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Publications and Writings by Washington Federations of Teachers and Members, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - News Releases, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Legislation, 1955-1968 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Office Notes and Correspondence: Probably from the Desk of Seattle Federation of Teachers President Ken Warren, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - LISTS, 1945-1968; SERIES VII (Box-folder 3/12-3/13)
    - Membership Lists, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Mailing Lists and Lists of Participants/Delegates/Officers, 1945-1967 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - PUBLICATIONS, LEAFLETS, AND MEMBER PETITIONS, 1946-1973; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 4/1-5/5)
    - Newsletters (1 of 2), 1953-1968 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Newsletters (2 of 2), 1953-1968 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Newspapers (1 of 2), 1963-1971 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Newspapers (2 of 2), 1963-1971 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - News Clippings (1 of 2), 1946-1968 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - News Clippings (2 of 2), 1946-1968 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Member Questionnaires, Advertisements, Forms, 1949-1968 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Pamphlets, 1946-1968 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Petitions: Washington Junior High School Safety, Strike for Levy, Summer Pay Schedule, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Leaflets: Grievances and Contract Negotiations (1 of 2), 1953-1973 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Leaflets: Grievances and Contract Negotiations (2 of 2), 1953-1973 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Magazine Reprints, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 5/5)
- American Federation of Teachers Local 200 Records, 1943-1974; 1909-004; 5.42 cubic feet 6 boxes
  Records related to the activities of the American Federation of Teachers Local 200. Includes reports, grievances and employer relations, financial records, meeting minutes, correspondence, photographs and ephemera, subject files, and news clippings and publications.
  - REPORTS, 1967-1971; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1-1/5)
    - Activity Report, 1970 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Annual Service Report: Fletcher, Marian F.: Brighton, 1971 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Personnel Report and Teaching Certificate Issues: Inglis, Julia Q.: Cleveland, 1971 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Reports - Washington State Labor Council, 1970 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Seattle Teachers Association Publications; Seattle Schools Conditions Study, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - GRIEVANCES AND EMPLOYER RELATIONS, 1964-1971; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/6-1/27)
    - Edmonds School Board Case: Edmonds High School Spanish Teacher Mrs. Marian Penichet, 1964 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Strike at St. Johns University by United Federation of College Teachers: Press and Correspondence, 1965 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Arbitrations Against Seattle School District: Stipends, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Grievances Against Seattle Public Schools, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - California Table Grape Boycott, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Grievances: Greenwood Elementary: Teacher Vacancies not Advertised, 1970 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Grievances: Hamilton Junior High: Closure of Special Education Classroom, 1970 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Grievance: "Northwest Retarded Center": Transfer Request not Granted, 1970 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Grievance: Rainier Beach: Reimbursement for Stolen Property; Seattle Children's Home: Petition for Additional Teachers, 1970 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Grievance: Safety/Traffic Education: Discrimination, 1970 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Disciplinary Letter: Queen Anne High School: Mistreatment of Students, 1970 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Agreement and Correspondence Regarding Release Time, 1970 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Issue over Suspension of a Student: Jane Addams Junior High, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Grievance: Sharples Junior High School: Memo Instructing Teachers not to Physically Handle Students in non-Self-Defense Situations, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Arbitration: Perishing Baldwin v. Seattle School District #1. American Arbitration Association Case No. 75-39-0002-71, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Grievance: West Seattle Street Academy, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Memoranda, Notes, and Minutes: Garfield High School: Language Arts Curriculum Guide, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Leave Request Issues: Warren, Kenneth R. and Dunphy, Shirley, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - King County Superior Court Case No. 719016: Subs in Assigned Positions, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Grievance: Marshall Junior High: Salary Error, 1971 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Interpersonal Issues: Saint Euphrasia High School: Principal v. Teachers, 1971 (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Grievance: Misassignment of Work, Back Salary Due, 1971 (Box-folder 1/27)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1943-1972; SERIES III (Box-folder 1/28-1/52)
    - American Federation of Teachers Financial Records, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 1/28)
    - Washington State Teachers' Retirement System: Computing Retirement Benefits, 1968 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Seattle Federation of Teachers: Budgets, Financial Correspondence, Minutes of Ad Hoc Desegregation Committee, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Dues Authorizations and Cancellations: Membership for Seattle Federation of Teachers (1 of 2), 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Dues Authorizations and Cancellations: Membership for Seattle Federation of Teachers (2 of 2), 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Seattle Federation of Teachers: Financial Statements, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Seattle Federation of Teachers: Financial Statements, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 1/34)
    - Salary Change Requests: Everett Federation of Teachers, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 1/35)
    - Bank Account Statements with Peoples National Bank: Everett Federation of Teachers No. 772, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 1/36)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: Ledger, 1943-1966 (Box-folder 1/37)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: Ledger, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 1/38)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: Invoices, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 1/39)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: Budgeting and Planning: Convention Expenses, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 1/40)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: Financial Statements and Correspondence, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 1/41)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: Scholarships, 1955-1965 (Box-folder 1/42)
    - Seattle School District #1 Budget; Membership Eligibility, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/43)
    - Dues Authorizations, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1/44)
    - Salary Schedule (1 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1/45)
    - Salary Schedule (2 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1/46)
    - Pay Scales for Custodians, 1968 (Box-folder 1/47)
    - Administrative and Teacher Salary Schedules, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 1/48)
    - Summer Pay, 1969 (Box-folder 1/49)
    - Salaries, Washington Education Association (WEA) Study, 1954, 1951-1956 (Box-folder 1/50)
    - Salary Schedules for Various Districts, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 1/51)
    - Statewide Minimum Salary Schedule, 1958 (Box-folder 1/52)
  - MEETING MINUTES, 1949-1971; SERIES IV (Box-folder 1/53-2/12)
    - Regular School Board Meeting Minutes (1 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1/53)
    - Regular School Board Meeting Minutes (2 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1/54)
    - School Board Meeting Minutes and Memoranda (1 of 2), 1970-1971 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - School Board Meeting Minutes and Memoranda (2 of 2), 1970-1971 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Washington State Federation of Teachers: Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1953-1962 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Washington State Federation of Teachers: Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Summary Minutes: Meetings of Representatives of Seattle Federation of Teachers and the Superintendent, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Memoranda and Meeting Minutes (1 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Memoranda and Meeting Minutes (2 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Seattle Federation of Teachers Executive Board Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: Meeting Minutes, Press, Financial Reports, Organizing and Contract Negotiations Materials, 1949-1953 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: Executive Board and Regular Meeting Minutes, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: Executive Board, Regular, and Committee Meeting Minutes, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1951-1971; SERIES V (Box-folder 2/13-3/7)
    - American Federation of Teachers: Correspondence and Publications (1 of 2), 1951-1966 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - American Federation of Teachers: Correspondence and Publications (2 of 2), 1951-1966 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Correspondence: Cora B. Oberholtzer: President, Local 772 Everett Federation of Teachers, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: President Robert A. Wickstrom: Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: President Wil Knutsen: Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Everett Federation of Teachers: President Ross K. Rieder Correspondence, 1965 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Ross K. Rieder, President, Everett Federation of Teachers Local 772: Correspondence, Press Clippings, and Minutes: January-June, 1966 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Ross K. Rieder, President, Everett Federation of Teachers Local 772: Correspondence, Press Clippings, and Minutes: June-November, 1966 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Ross K. Rieder, President, Everett Federation of Teachers Local 772: Correspondence, Press Clippings, and Minutes: September-December, 1966 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Ross K. Rieder, President, Everett Federation of Teachers Local 772: Correspondence, Press Clippings, and Minutes: December-February, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Ross K. Rieder, President, Everett Federation of Teachers Local 772: Correspondence, Press Clippings, and Minutes: November-June, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Ross K. Rieder, President, Everett Federation of Teachers Local 772: Correspondence, Press Clippings, and Minutes, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Correspondence from Kenneth G. Warren, President, Seattle Federation of Teachers, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Stanton C. Bloom Personal Papers, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Press on Science; Correspondence from John Dehalanty, SFT Building Representative, 1969 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Field Representative-Correspondence, 1969 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Administrative Correspondence Regarding Publication of The American Teacher, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Membership Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Correspondence Regarding Personnel: Superintendent Forbes Bottomly, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - SUBJECT FILES, 1950-1973; SERIES VI (Box-folder 3/8-4/40)
    - Conventions, 1959-1970; Subseries A (Box-folder 3/8-3/12)
      - Report of 1970 National Education Association Convention (Box-folder 3/8)
      - American Federation of Teachers Convention (1 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/9)
      - American Federation of Teachers Convention (2 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/10)
      - National Education Association (NEA) Convention, 1970 (Box-folder 3/11)
      - Washington State Federation of Teachers: Convention Resolutions, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Organizing, 1969-1971; Subseries B (Box-folder 3/13-3/19)
      - Proposal for Agency Shop: Seeking Dues from Non-Members working in Organized Shops, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/13)
      - University of Washington, Student Federation of Teachers, 1969 (Box-folder 3/14)
      - University of Washington, Brotherhood of Teaching Assistants, 1969 (Box-folder 3/15)
      - Para-professionals: Organizing, Correspondence, and Collective Bargaining (1 of 3), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/16)
      - Para-professionals: Organizing, Correspondence, and Collective Bargaining (2 of 3), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/17)
      - Para-professionals: Organizing, Correspondence, and Collective Bargaining (3 of 3), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/18)
      - Seattle Federation of Teachers Organizing, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Central Area School Council and Community Control of Schools in Central and South Seattle, 1968-1971; Subseries C (Box-folder 3/20-3/32)
      - Central Area School Council: Publications and Meeting Minutes, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 3/20)
      - Plan for Decentralization of Advisory School Councils in Seattle, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/21)
      - Issue: Transfers of Teachers out of Central Region, 1970 (Box-folder 3/22)
      - Faculty Reduction at Rainier Beach Junior and Senior High School, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/23)
      - Decentralization and Community Control of Schools, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/24)
      - Correspondence: Battelle Seattle Research Center: Meeting of Teacher Advisory Group for Seattle Academy Concept, 1969 (Box-folder 3/25)
      - Seattle School District's Proposed Southeast Education Center: Newsletter, General Recommendations, Planning Recommendations, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3/26)
      - Parent Teacher Association (PTA), 1968-1970 (Box-folder 3/27)
      - Central Area School Council: Racism in Curriculum, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/28)
      - Central Area School Council: Minutes, Evaluations, Budgets, Correspondence, Press (1 of 4), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/29)
      - Central Area School Council: Minutes, Evaluations, Budgets, Correspondence, Press (2 of 4), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/30)
      - Central Area School Council: Minutes, Evaluations, Budgets, Correspondence, Press (3 of 4), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/31)
      - Central Area School Council: Minutes, Evaluations, Budgets, Correspondence, Press (4 of 4), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/32)
    - Desegregation and Racial Issues, 1967-1971; Subseries D (Box-folder 3/33-4/2)
      - Desegregation Plan: Student Bussing, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/33)